http://www.booterstown.dublin.anglican.org/index.php/data-privacy-policy/

Parish Privacy Policy
The Parishes of Booterstown and Carysfort with Mount Merrion
The United Dioceses of Dublin and Glendalough
Overview
The Parishes of Booterstown and Carysfort with Mount Merrion (hereafter ‘the parishes’) respect the privacy and data protection rights of individuals (both staff and members of the public), in compliance with the General Data Protection Regulation. This document outlines the parishes’ obligations to ensure compliance with the requirements of the General Data Protection Regulation and outlines how that commitment is carried out with regards to the collection and use of personal data.
Purpose
The parishes must comply with the data protection principles set out in the General Data Protection Regulation. This policy outlines the conditions that must be satisfied in relation to the processing of personal data.
1. Your personal data – what is it?
Personal data relates to a living individual who can be identified from that data.
Identification can be by the information alone or in conjunction with any other information in the data controller’s possession or likely to come into such possession. The processing of personal data is governed by the General Data Protection Regulation (the “GDPR”).
2. Who are we?
The Parishes are the data controller (contact details below).
This means the parishes decides how your personal data is processed and for what purposes.
3. How do we process your personal data?
The Parishes comply with their obligations under the “GDPR” by keeping personal data up to date; by storing and destroying it securely; by not collecting or retaining excessive amounts of data; by protecting personal data from loss, misuse, unauthorised access and disclosure and by ensuring that appropriate technical measures are in place to protect personal data.
We use your personal data for the following purposes: –
•	To enable us to provide a voluntary service in a particular geographical area as specified in our constitution;
•	To administer membership records;
•	To fundraise and promote the interests of the churches;
•	To manage our employees and volunteers;
•	To maintain our own accounts and records;
•	To inform you of news, events, activities and services;
•	To share your contact details with the Diocesan office so they can keep you informed about news in the diocese and events, activities and services that will be occurring in the diocese and in which you may be interested;
•	To carry out other activities in the legitimate interests of the administration of the parishes
4. What is the legal basis for processing your personal data?
•	Explicit consent of the data subject so that we can keep you informed about news, events, activities and services and process your gift aid donations and keep you informed about parochial and diocesan events
•	Processing is necessary for carrying out obligations under employment, social security or social protection law, or a collective agreement
•	Processing is carried out by a not-for-profit body with a political, philosophical, religious or trade union aim provided:
o	the processing relates only to members or former members (or those who have regular contact with it in connection with those purposes); and
o	there is no disclosure to a third party without consent
5. Sharing your personal data
Your personal data will be treated as strictly confidential and will only be shared with other members of the churches in order to carry out a service to other church members or for purposes connected with the church. We will only share your data with third parties outside of the parishes with your consent.
6. How long do we keep your personal data ?
We keep data in accordance with the guidance set out within Irish Data Protection Legislation.
Specifically, we retain membership data while it is still current; data relating to financial giving and associated paperwork for up to 6 years after the calendar year to which they relate; and parishes registers (baptisms, marriages, funerals) permanently.
7. Your rights and your personal data
Unless subject to an exemption under the GDPR, you have the following rights with respect to your personal data: –
•	The right to request a copy of your personal data which the parishes hold about you
•	The right to request that the Parishes correct any personal data if it is found to be inaccurate or out of date
•	The right to request your personal data is erased where it is no longer necessary for the Parishes to retain such data
•	The right to withdraw your consent to the processing at any time
•	The right to request that the data controller provide the data subject with his/her personal data and where possible, to transmit that data directly to another data controller, (known as the right to data portability), (where applicable)
[Only applies where the processing is based on consent or is necessary for the performance of a contract with the data subject and in either case the data controller processes the data by automated means]
•	The right, where there is a dispute in relation to the accuracy or processing of your personal data, to request a restriction is placed on further processing
•	The right to object to the processing of personal data, (where applicable)
[Only applies where processing is based on legitimate interests (or the performance of a task in the public interest/exercise of official authority); direct marketing and processing for the purposes of scientific/historical research and statistics]
•	The right to lodge a complaint with the Data Protection Commissioner (Ireland)
8. Further processing
If we wish to use your personal data for a new purpose, not covered by this Data Privacy Notice, then we will provide you with a new notice. The new notice will explain the new use of your personal data prior to commencing the processing. It will set out the relevant purposes and processing conditions. Where and whenever necessary, we will seek your prior consent to the new processing.
9. Data Storage, breach and Destruction
Your personal data will be stored securely on the parishes’ IT systems, and where relevant, hard copies will be stored in the parishes’ safes.
Where explicit consent to hold and process personal data is not provided it will be deleted in both hard and soft format
Accidental loss or destruction of data, or any instance of a data breach, will be notified to the Data Protection Commissioner
10. Contact Details
To exercise all relevant rights, queries of complaints please in the first instance contact the Rector, The Rectory, Cross Avenue, Booterstown, Blackrock, County Dublin.
A94 W7R6.
booterstownandmountmerrion@gmail.com
You can contact the Data Protection Commissioner (Ireland) on +353 (0761) 104 800; via email info@dataprotection.ie
or by writing to:
The Data Protection Commissioner, Canal House, Station Road, Portarlington, County Laois, R32 AP23
